<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-25T03:04:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Art of Growing Roots in London</title><subtitle>Another blog of another Spaniard settled in the UK trying to grow some roots in London. By Maikel</subtitle><entry><title type="html">In a limbo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/25/In-a-limbo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In a limbo" /><published>2018-01-25T00:00:01+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-25T00:00:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/25/In-a-limbo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/25/In-a-limbo.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;context-is-everything&quot;&gt;Context is everything&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am moving to a flat that costs 750 pounds per month the room with my best friend. The flat is nearby the one I live now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one in which I currently live is too small and my flatmate is quite distracting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The degree I am studying is distance learning, which means I study and prepare exams and assignments from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am finishing my degree with the Open University and that means I’ve got the hardest module now: &lt;strong&gt;The Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means I can’t do with distractions in the place in which I work, home. Hence why I am moving out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently pay very little rent and I cover it by my freelance video editing job that I do during the weekends, I live a quite frugal life with very little expenses. I’ve got quite cheap hobbies, I walk a lot so … I don’t really spend what I earn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video editing gig doesn’t proportionate enough income to pay 750 per month in rent plus bills. Therefore I need a much more stable source of income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best-friend currently live with someone, their contract will finish in the 23rd of March, &lt;em&gt;less than two months from now&lt;/em&gt; and he doesn’t like his flatmate. The idea is to either me moving there and renewing contract or both moving elsewhere locally and take a flat between both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-difficulty&quot;&gt;The difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context given the added difficulty is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve already started my degree project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I should have a job &lt;strong&gt;by the beginning of February&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have another module of university to complete at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time is running out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7.50 an hour jobs (easy to find) won’t cover rent and food. Let alone the agency won’t accept someone on minimum wage to sign a 12 month contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;latest-news&quot;&gt;Latest news&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I’m expecting an answer from an opportunity to work as Assistant Accountant, in the meantime I keep applying daily. I had that interview last Saturday (20th of January) but the person who interview me needs to have the “go ahead” from the owner of the business. In the meantime I’m in a limbo and I haven’t receive not one single phone call from all the jobs I’ve applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-am-i-applying-for&quot;&gt;What am I applying for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I search in the career pages from the councils around me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.westminster.gov.uk/job-search.html&quot;&gt;Hammersmith and Fulham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ealing.gov.uk/homepage/28/jobs&quot;&gt;Ealing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hounslow.gov.uk/info/20003/jobs_careers_and_adult_learning&quot;&gt;Hounslow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.richmondandwandsworth.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;Richmond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And applied for jobs as Administrative Assistant and Office Clerk related jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did the same with all the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhsjobs.com/job_search/s7/Administrative_services?_ts=1&quot;&gt;hospitals around me&lt;/a&gt;. Applying for around 14 vacancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/nhsapplications.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also applied to around a hundred jobs admin related in Reed.co.uk and Cv-Library.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running out of ideas and patience, hence why today I decided to start this blog to help me clear my mind and figure out what am I going to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a especially delicate situation for the simple fact that it doesn’t just involve me, it also involves my best friend, I can’t let him down. If I can’t find anything it also affects him.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Context is everything I am moving to a flat that costs 750 pounds per month the room with my best friend. The flat is nearby the one I live now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">8 hours playing sudokus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/24/8-hours-playing-sudokus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="8 hours playing sudokus" /><published>2018-01-24T22:00:01+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T22:00:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/24/8-hours-playing-sudokus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/24/8-hours-playing-sudokus.html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you were paid for playing sudokus, they are all the same with only slighly variations and your career progression is simply to find different ways to play it or to do it faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is what a job in Software Development &lt;strong&gt;as an employee&lt;/strong&gt; looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re constrained in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The programming language you can use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The frameworks you can use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ideas that you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically someone comes with a piece of a very simple problem, in Soft.Devel terms this is called a specification and you’ve got to write the code for it. This is rarely interesting bits or puzzles to solve but always the same related stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now you know why I don’t want to work as a Software Developer for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maikel.uk&quot;&gt;maikel.uk&lt;/a&gt;, if I had to prepare for just one employer I would just know a fraction of what I wrote there. Being a freelancer preserves the fun of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can love sudokus, but if you do the same one every working day of the year for the rest of your life you’ll hate it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Imagine that you were paid for playing sudokus, they are all the same with only slighly variations and your career progression is simply to find different ways to play it or to do it faster.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/2018/01/24/8-hours-playing-sudokus0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test" /><published>2018-01-24T19:00:01+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T19:00:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/2018/01/24/8-hours-playing-sudokus0</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/2018/01/24/8-hours-playing-sudokus0.html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you were paid for playing sudokus, they are all the same with only slighly variations and your career progression is simply to find different ways to play it or to do it faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is what a job in Software Development &lt;strong&gt;as an employee&lt;/strong&gt; looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re constrained in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The programming language you can use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The frameworks you can use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ideas that you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically someone comes with a piece of a very simple problem, in Soft.Devel terms this is called a specification and you’ve got to write the code for it. This is rarely interesting bits or puzzles to solve but always the same related stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now you know why I don’t want to work as a Software Developer for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maikel.uk&quot;&gt;maikel.uk&lt;/a&gt;, if I had to prepare for just one employer I would just know a fraction of what I wrote there. Being a freelancer preserves the fun of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can love sudokus, but if you do the same one every working day of the year for the rest of your life you’ll hate it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Imagine that you were paid for playing sudokus, they are all the same with only slighly variations and your career progression is simply to find different ways to play it or to do it faster.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Once Upon a Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/24/once-upon-a-time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Once Upon a Time" /><published>2018-01-24T18:00:01+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T18:00:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/24/once-upon-a-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jobseeking/project/2018/01/24/once-upon-a-time.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-this&quot;&gt;So, what is this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a blog, created in &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; a simple static page creator for blogs that does not require a database. I didn’t know how to use it, never heard of it, until two hours ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 3pm today I started a search about blogging platforms, I’m already aware and knowledgeable of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/download/&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; (I had a self-hosted blog for about 7 years) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; so I wanted a bit of a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone through the basics, then set it up in Github Pages and modified my domain configuration to use blog.maikel.uk instead of maikeldotuk.github.io. I already know markup because of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&quot;www.reddit.com&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;) so that’s the easy part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-what-will-this-blog-be-about&quot;&gt;And what will this blog be about?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to keep track here of my job-seeking activities, writing the challenges I’m finding so I can overcome them. Sometimes thinking out loud helps find solutions, &lt;strong&gt;for me is writing what helps.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I find a a job I’ll carry on talking about how &lt;a href=&quot;http://css2.open.ac.uk/outis/descs/mc_courses/TM470.htm&quot;&gt;my project&lt;/a&gt; at university is going. Which is the main reason I’m trying to find a job so quickly: my project’s first TMA is due on March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-you-a-student&quot;&gt;Are you a student?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed I am, I study Computing Science in the &lt;a href=&quot;www.open.ac.uk&quot;&gt;Open University&lt;/a&gt;, the leading distance learning education of the UK. I started in 2013 a BSc in Computing and IT, with a speciality on Software Development. The entire degree is 360 credits and I’ve completed already 300 of them. I’m right now doing the remaining 60 and I’ll finish it by September 2018. Yep, that’s in 8 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-you-do-when-you-graduate&quot;&gt;What will you do when you graduate?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing much. I took the degree because I didn’t want to waste my time in the UK. I came here originally just to learn English, then stayed for that degree. Then I stop wanting to move elsewhere. I’ve have my experiences working as an employee as a Software Developer and honestly &lt;strong&gt;I just did’t like it&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s a reason Soft.Devel jobs are paid so highly, very few people would actually enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people believe that you spend the day programming stuff you actually love, but that’s not the reality, you end up being constrained to some programming language, some framework and doing menial stuff continuously for others. Stuff you don’t believe in. You could argue that most jobs are like that, I can counter-argue that most jobs don’t consist on solving-sudokus non-stop. And that’s what programming is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to do is to use my knowledge in &lt;strong&gt;freelance&lt;/strong&gt; jobs on my spare time and personal projects. That won’t limit me on what I can and cannot learn. For an overview of what I am already knowledgeable (but not limited) off have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maikel.uk&quot;&gt;maikel.uk&lt;/a&gt; and you will see my skillset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-have-you-done-in-the-past&quot;&gt;What have you done in the past?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in many sort of jobs, I’ve been:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estate Agency Coordinator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaner (yes, cleaner, and worse, enjoyed it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shift Manager for a gay sauna.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call centre agent (Rentalcars, Natwest Mortgages, Orange).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caretaker for one of London’s councils.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IT Operator in a data centre for 2 banks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IT Support for an European Union organism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list never ends and that’s not counting what I’ve done as freelancer, currently I keep all the bills paid by editing videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-really-want-to-do-now&quot;&gt;What do you really want to do now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to work in an office setting because I enjoy excelling at what I do. It keeps me going. I type above 90 words per minute and I automate almost everything I do with a computer. Using this knowledge I usually stand out in office jobs that require the user of a computer. I don’t want to try more roles, I want to grow roots in a company. My interest are two-fold, on one side you’ve got what I really want to do as an &lt;em&gt;employee&lt;/em&gt; and on the other side what I want to do on my spare time &lt;em&gt;freelancing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an employee I look for stability, as a freelancer I look for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;as-an-employee&quot;&gt;As an employee:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stability and long-term are a must so I’m looking for roles of the type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Entry / Typist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administrator Assistant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accountant Assistant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;as-freelancer&quot;&gt;As freelancer:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason I don’t want to try being a Software Developer as a career goal is because I’ve got too many interests. These are the things I can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NativeScript a programmer. This is a platform that allows you to design apps that are cross-platform compatible iOS and Android.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angular developer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full stack javascript developer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web Scraper with Python and Scrapy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Front-end Web Developer.
As you see this covers too many disciplines and evolves with time, reason for which I wouldn’t ever enjoy being prisoner of a framework and programming language for any company. I rather do eventual contracted jobs so I can move on after I finish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to navigate and explore this brand new blog and raise any questions to the email below shall you wish to ask me anything. I might implement later a commenting feature.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So, what is this? This is a blog, created in Jekyll a simple static page creator for blogs that does not require a database. I didn’t know how to use it, never heard of it, until two hours ago.</summary></entry></feed>